Benjamin Rose

t: 207.939.3126 e: benrose207@gmail.com San Francisco, CA Portfolio Linkedin GitHub

Skills JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Webpack, Git, jQuery, Heroku, Mongoose, Google Analytics, Google Data Studio, Product Management

Projects

AllHikes live site github

JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, CSS3, AWS, MapBox API, Heroku, Webpack

Site on which users can find information about hikes, as well as add reviews and photos. Inspired by AllTrails.com.

- Built dynamic AJAX functions using the componentDidMount lifecycle method to pull different reviews or photos depending on the context, improving consistency of user experience by reusing React components.
- Leveraged Rails polymorphic associations with hike and review tags for DRYer code and increased scalability.
- Integrated MapBox APIs for map rendering, static images, & directions to create a seamless user experience.

Sheep on the Lam live site | github

JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5 Canvas

Browser-based game in which the user has to herd sheep back into their pasture.

- Built collision response functions with JavaScript and requestAnimationFrame to simulate sheep movements.
- Created shared classes using JavaScript's prototypal inheritance for DRY code and scaling of game complexity.
- Leveraged HTML5 Canvas API with custom sprite sheets for dynamic and fun user experience.

ReBond live site | github

React , Redux , JavaScript , Node.js , Express.js , MongoDB , Materialize , CSS3 , Mongoose , SendGrid , Heroku An app to facilitate meetups between already-established groups of people, based on personal interests and passions.

- Diagrammed React component architecture to streamline app creation and align data flow between and front-end Axios calls and Redux cycle and backend Mongoose models and route handlers.
- Leveraged query strings using Javascript to create unique sign-up URLs, streamlining new user experience.
- Integrated SendGrid's email platform to send users event invites, facilitating easier user interaction with the app

Experience

Product Manager | Go Overseas | May 2018 - March 2020

- Facilitated all feature development for site, consistently improving user experience on mobile and desktop.
- Implemented story points & sprint planning to improve agile development processes and work estimates.
- Built reports and dashboards using SQL, Google Analytics, and Google Data Studio, which improved employee access to company metrics and saved software engineers hours of time per week.

Analyst | Computer Courage | October 2016 - May 2018

- Implemented new cloud services and procedures/policies for clients, streamlining employee processes.
- Spearheaded security consulting for clients to ensure that data and practices met industry best practices.

Business Analyst | EF Education First | March 2014 - July 2016

- Facilitated creation of custom CRM for 1200+ users on 3 continents, improving team efficiencies and innovation.
- Defined & prioritized features via UX research, and conveyed to engineers to incorporate in software releases.

Education

App Academy | Summer 2020 | San Francisco, CA

Immersive software development course with focus on full stack web development and < 3% acceptance rate.

Wesleyan University | 2008 - 2012 | Middletown, CT

BA History and Iberian Studies